Curriculum Vitae

Personal Information

Name: Gábor Forgács

Telephone: +36-70-949-949-8 Email: <u>forgacsg@gmail.com</u>

no forgacsg.github.io



Summary

I am a problem solver with excellent speaking and writing skills. I am able to work on my own initiative as well as part of a team to achieve the best results possible. I have experience in data analytics with Python and R as well as developing data warehouses and operationalising machine learning models both on-prem and in the cloud (GCP). I am a Google Certified Professional Data Engineer. I also have an interest in web development and completed an online bootcamp during the summer of 2020.

Relevant Skills

- Python: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib,
 Scikit-Learn, Flask, Plotly, Dash
- R: dplyr, ggplot2, tidyverse, R Shiny
- Javascript: MERN stack, D3.js
- SQL: T-SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, BQ
- NoSQL: MongoDB, Cloud Firestore

- Docker
- Git and Gitlab CI/CD
- Dashboarding tools: Power BI | Tableaum | Qlik
- GIS: Leaflet, QGIS, Spatial Databases (PostGIS)

Work Experience

2022 – Data Scientist

British Telecom ROC.

2019 – 2022 Senior Data Analyst

British Telecom ROC.

- Analysis of ticket data from various service desk systems
- Data modelling and predictions with Python using ScikitLearn & other packages
- Building API's with Flask
- Dashboard development in Qlik and Python (Dash)
- Deployment with Docker and GitLab CI

2017 – 2019: IT Business Analyst (Business Intelligence)

Cushman & Wakefield

- ETL of client data in Python and SQL Server
- Developing dashboards and reports in PowerBI and Tableau
- Historical Payment Reconciliation for key clients based on generated cash-flow

2016 – 2017: **System Analyst**

Cushman & Wakefield

- Ensuring data quality for benchmarking
- Reporting user activity trends, benchmarking data pool contents on a quarterly basis
- Project coordination with external developers

2012 – 2016: English Language Teacher

Tudomány Language School

References: Ericsson, Ixenit, Bayer, British American Tobacco, Deloitte

2014 – 2015: Junior Research Fellow

Budapest University of Technology and Economics, Department of History and

Philosophy of Science

2009 – 2011: English Language Teacher

Institution for the Education of Insurance Studies

Education

2017 – 2018: Microsoft Professional Program in Data Science

2011 – 2014: Graduate student at the Budapest University of Technology and Economics,

Department of History and Philosophy of Science

2009: Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (University of Pécs)

2009: Master of Arts in Teaching Philosophy (University of Pécs)

Certificates

Google Cloud Certified Professional Data Engineer

Udemy: The Complete 2020 Web Development Bootcamp

• Coursera: Foundations of Business Strategy

Coursera: Competitive Strategy

• EdX: Networks, Crowds and Markets

Coursera: Logic: Language and Information 2

Awards, Honours and Memberships

2009: Second Place at the XXIX. Biannual National Scholarly Competition for Students – in

the category of English Theoretical and Descriptive Linguistics

2008: CEEPUS research scholarship at the Karl Franzens Universität, Graz

2005 – 2009: member of the University of Pécs Kerényi Károly Extracurricular Study Fraternity,

Senior in 2007-2008

Language Proficiency

English
 C2 - Master of Arts in Teaching English Language and Literature (2009)

• German B2 TELC intermediate exam, type "C"